simplicable.com 2018-08-24

# Privacy Policy - Simplicable

posted by , January 28, 2004 updated on June 02, 2018

Simplicable takes your privacy seriously. Please read the following to learn more about our privacy policy.

## What This Privacy Policy Covers

This policy covers how Simplicable treats personal information that Simplicable collects and receives, including information related to your past use of Simplicable products and services. Personal information is information about you that is personally identifiable like your name, address, email address, or phone number. This policy does not apply to the practices of companies that Simplicable does not own or control, or to people that Simplicable does not employ or manage. In addition, certain Simplicable advertising and technology partners have their own privacy statements.

## Information Collection and Use General

Simplicable does not retain any personal information about you in a database. Simplicable collects information in the following ways:a. To record the state of our user interface on your device. For example, if you close a menu we may set a cookie to keep that menu closed on each page you visit. This is not used to identify anything about you or to build a profile about you.b. Cookies that are required to implement the technologies that underlie the Simplicable service. For example, to direct your requests to a server in your region to speed up our service. These cookies are set by third party cloud infrastructure companies used by Simplicable (including CloudFlare).c. Simplicable accepts inquiries through a contact page. This allows you to send us a message and your email address so that we can respond. We do not do any type of email marketing nor do we normally share these emails with third parties (see Disclosure by Law below for exceptions). Contact information is retained only as long as is reasonable to service the inquiry and maintain a record of interactions with users. d. Simplicable places third party ads in our pages. These third parties (including Google) place and read cookies on your browser and use web beacons to collect information. More information about Google privacy can be found here:<https://www.google.com/policies/technologies/partner-sites/>e. Simplicable uses a third party analytics service (Google Analytics) to capture statistics about visitors to our sites. This third party (Google) places and reads cookies on your browser to collect information. This is essential to our service as it is required to plan, operate, monitor and optimize the service. **We do not have the service "Advertising Features" enabled on Google Analytics. This means that we do not collect or use demographic information about you such as your age, gender or interests.** More information about Google privacy can be found here:<https://www.google.com/policies/technologies/partner-sites/>

## Photography

Simplicable uses photographs on our site that are used for journalistic, academic, artistic and/or literary expression depending on the context. This usually takes the form of us featuring the artwork of a third party photographer on our site. Such photos may include photographs of crowds, public events or individuals such that individuals may be recognizable. As part of our editorial process, we make sure that we never publish a photo that is likely to be embarrassing to an individual. If your face appears on Simplicable in a way that makes you uncomfortable, please [let us know](https://simplicable.com/ContactUsSubjectServlet) and we will remove it. The photographs on Simplicable are the copyright of third parties who have typically published these photos in other public venues. The contact details of each photographer can be found by taking the "credits & copyrights" link on the bottom of the page where it appears.

## Information Sharing and Disclosure

Simplicable does not directly collect information about you in our databases. However, our pages include advertising and analytics services from third parties. We use third parties to serve ads when you visit our website. These companies (including Google) may use information about your visits in order to provide ads on this site and other sites about goods and services that may be of interest to you.

## Confidentiality and Security

We limit access to personal information about you to employees who we believe reasonably need to come into contact with that information to provide products or services to you or in order to do their jobs. We have physical, electronic, and procedural safeguards that comply with federal regulations to protect personal information about you.

## Disclosure by Law

Simplicable may disclose information you provide if required to do so by law, at the request of a third party, or if we, in our sole discretion, believe that disclosure is reasonable to (1) comply with the law, requests or orders from law enforcement, or any legal process (whether or not such disclosure is required by applicable law); (2) protect or defend Simplicable's rights or property; or (3) protect someone's health or safety.

## Legal Basis for Processing (EEA only):

If you are an individual from the European Economic Area (EEA), please note that our legal basis for collecting and using your personal information will depend on the personal information collected and the specific context in which we collect it. We normally will collect personal information from you only where: (a) we have your consent to do so, (b) where we need your personal information to perform a contract with you (e.g. to deliver the Simplicable service you have requested), or (c) where the processing is in our legitimate interests. Please note that in most cases, if you do not provide the requested information, Simplicable will not be able to provide the requested service to you.Where we rely on your consent to process your personal data, you have the right to withdraw or decline consent at any time. Where we rely on our legitimate interests to process your personal data, you have the right to object.If you have any questions about or need further information concerning the legal basis on which we collect and use your personal information, please contact us using [this form](https://simplicable.com/ContactUsSubjectServlet).

## Your rights with regard to personal data

Residents of the European Economic Area and certain other jurisdictions have rights with regards to their data such as the right to access, delete and modify their data. Simplicable does not record any personal information about you in our databases. However, our partner Google does set cookies related to the analytics and ads on this site. Information about the privacy of these services and your rights related to data stored by these services can be found here:<https://www.google.com/policies/technologies/partner-sites/>You can elect to opt-out of certain types of information collection by using our [consent tool](https://simplicable.com/new/consent-tool).

## Changes to this Privacy Policy

Simplicable may update this policy. We will notify you about significant changes in the way we treat personal information by placing a prominent notice on our site.

## [Trending](https://simplicable.com/trends)

The most popular articles on Simplicable in the past day.

## [New Articles](https://simplicable.com/new)

Recent posts or updates on Simplicable.

The difference between modern and contemporary as it applies to ideas, art, architecture, literature and other works.  

---|---|---
